Mark Ernest R. Matute

Aquarius By The Park, 3, Bedok Reservoir View, Singapore 478927 +65 98315311 - markernest.matute@gmail.com

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-matute/

Github - https://github.com/MarkMatute

Portfolio - https://markmatute.github.io/

PROFILE

Experienced Software Engineer working with latest technologies with JavaScript, PHP etc. Developing software applications with reliability, security and maintainability in mind both Front-end and Back-end applications. Advocate of TDD approach clean and simple code development.

SKILLS

- Back-End / API Development, JavaScript, TypeScript, TypeORM, NodeJS, REST, ExpressJS, Koa, Loopback, PHP, CodeIgniter
- CLI Development with NodeJS, Commander and Inquirer
- Front-End Development, ReactJS, Redux, AngularJS, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML
- API Stress Testing and reporting with JMeter
- Unit testing with Mocha and Chai
- Experienced with GIT and Agile Development(JIRA)
- Experienced in server configuration with Apache, Nginx, CentOS
- Databases, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres
- Objective-C, Java

EXPERIENCE

iHealth Labs Pte. Ltd.

Singapore

Software Engineer

March 2018 – present

- Develop API's using NodeJS, TypeScript, TypeORM, Koa, MongoDB and MySQL
- Developed Unit Testing Framework for the MILO Project using TypeScript, Mocha and Chai
- Developed Front-end features using React and Redux
- Developed CLI Tools to automate various tasks using NodeJS and TypeScript

EACOMM Corporation (Parti Time)

Manila, Philippines

PHP Consultant

November 2017 – March 2018

- Develop and design PHP powered projects with CodeIgniter
- Manage End to End Development upto deployment of PHP Projects
- Maintenance works for the servers

ISBX Inc. Manila, Philippines

Full-Stack Web And Mobile Developer

June 2017 - February 2018

- Develop REST API's using NodeJS, LoopbackJS, MongoDB, MySQL
- Develop Front-end applications using AngularJS and Bootstrap
- Implemented API Stress testing and reporting using JMeter
- Develop iOS Applications using Objective-C

EACOMM Corporation

Manila, Philippines

Software Developer

May 2016 – June 2017

- Develop and design PHP powered projects with CodeIgniter and WordPress
- Introduced usage of MVC for application development with PHP
- Develop and design REST API's with NodeJS and Java
- Maintenance works for the servers

EDUCATION

Bulacan State University

Philippines

BS Information Technology

Graduated Dean's Lister

Holy Spirit Academy of Malolos

Philippines

Secondary Education

Holy Spirit Academy of Malolos

Philippines

Elementary Education